[{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"1. After a miniaturist from this country forbade his Italian-born wife from painting, she responded with a self-portrait of her defiantly crossing her arms. In this country, an artist depicted a woman holding a paintbrush up to a rainbow to imbue it with color as part of her series of allegorical representations of composition, design, and genius. Barely discernible portraits of two female artists hang on the back wall in Johan Zoffany’s group portrait of several artists from this country. An artist threw down his brush in frustration while painting the nose of a woman from this country, who in a different portrait sits in a throne in front of two women who hold a dagger and a chalice. A Swiss-born female artist spent fifteen years in this country with the support of the author of the Discourses on Art. For 10 points, name this country in which Angelica Kauffman co-founded the Royal Academy with Joshua Reynolds. ","answer":"ANSWER: England [or United Kingdom; or Great Britain] <Painting and Sculpture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"2. In this state, Judge Taylor Beattie led the Peace and Order Committee in a massacre of striking black fieldworkers organized by a local branch of the Knights of Labor led by Junius Bailey. William Ivy Hair’s Carnival of Fury follows Robert Charles, who allegedly shot twenty-eight white people while fighting off thousands of rioters over several days in this state. Charles T. Howard obtained a charter for this state’s lottery company, which became known as the “Golden Octopus” for lavishly bribing politicians. Until it was taken down in 2017, an obelisk commemorated the White League’s attempt to depose William Pitt Kellogg from this state’s governorship in the Battle of Liberty Place. The Supreme Court U.S. v. Cruikshank overturned the convictions of participants in a mob that killed over 100 freedmen in this state’s Colfax Massacre. For 10 points, name this south central U.S. state where Homer Plessy was arrested for boarding a “Whites Only” car in New Orleans. ","answer":"ANSWER: Louisiana <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"3. In 2000, Thomas MacLaughlin headed a team that published a review of these events, including one that ensued after a doofus technician tried to add trichloromethane to a tank of solution at Wood River Junction. A pair of these events irreparably damaged a machine known as the Lady Godiva Device. A notorious example of these events was caused by a scientist accidentally letting a screwdriver slip from his hand, leading to his death after he saw their fluorescence-induced flashes of light. The scientists Harry Daghlian and Louis Slotin died as a result of two separate incidents of this type, which both on centered on the so-called “demon core,” a collection of plutonium initially meant to be used in America’s third atomic bomb. The common name of these refers to a situation in which the effective neutron multiplication factor is over one, creating a “divergent chain reaction.” For 10 points, name this kind of nuclear incident in which chain reactions occur in a collection of material that exceeds the namesake mass. ","answer":"ANSWER: criticality incidents [or critical excursion or a critical power excursion or divergent chain reaction before “divergent”; prompt on nuclear disasters or chain reactions; do not accept or prompt on “nuclear meltdowns.”] <Other Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"4. In a memoir, one of these people compares Naughty by Nature’s song “O.P.P” to “telling parables” while it plays on his cassette player in front of a crowd. In a novel, one of these people is enraged when a character uses as rolling paper a copy of the Narrative of the Life of Frederick Douglass that he found hidden behind a chalkboard. One of these people, who mispronounces the word “reconnaissance” as “rayconzar,” is nicknamed High-Tech. Inspired by his experiences as one of these people, a character writes the book The World Was Silent When We Died, which is interspersed with chapters of the novel in which he appears. The houseboy Ugwu is forced to become one of these people in Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie’s Half of a Yellow Sun. For 10 points, Ishmael Beah’s memoir A Long Way Gone chronicles the author’s experience as what type of combatant? ","answer":"ANSWER: child soldiers [or boy soldiers; prompt on partial answer] <World Literature> 4/18/2019 Play-In Game - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/1O09LlDOk8qhoQGZ6oOZSMbX2yy5qY5yc32miDANiwPU/edit 3/12 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Play-In Game |Page 3 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"5. A book by this social scientist discusses the Packers coach Dan Devine, whose dog was shot in front of his home after a losing season, to claim that human aggression is no longer a \"valuable survival\" behavior. In one of this psychologist’s experiments, confederates who were pretending to audition to represent the University of Minnesota on the show College Bowl were evaluated by intelligence after they pretended to make a blunder, such as spilling coffee. In one of his textbooks, this psychologist put forth his so-called \"first law,\" stating that people who do crazy things are not necessarily crazy. This psychologist discovered the \"pratfall effect\" and designed assignments that could only be completed if groups of students in a classroom cooperated with one another. For 10 points, name this psychologist who wrote the textbook The Social Animal and created the \"jigsaw\" technique of education. ","answer":"ANSWER: Elliot Aronson <Social Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"6. Protestors in this country disparaged three of its leaders with the slogan, \"A goatee beard, a paunch and spectacles are not what the people want!\" A protest in this country that sent several people to the “Yellow Misery” prison could have been averted had the protestors known the government had rescinded its increased work quotas at VEBs. This country’s legislature passed its first ever non-unanimous resolution in a 1972 vote legalizing abortion. A June 1953 uprising took place in this country, whose youth attended “blue masses,” rock concerts held in churches. The Disney film Night Crossing fictionalized a family's escape from this country in an improvised hot-air balloon. Vacationers in this country often drove to nude beaches in their Trabants. For 10 points, name this Communist country whose population was monitored by the Stasi secret police. ","answer":"ANSWER: East Germany [or German Democratic Republic; or GDR; or DDR; or Deutsche Demokratische Republik; prompt on Germany] <European History.> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"7. A poem titled for this time period laments the deaths of Philander and Narcissa, and issues warnings like “All men think all men mortal, but themselves” and “Procrastination is the thief of time”to its addressee, Lorenzo. Along with its author’s Conjectures on Original Composition, that set of nine poems titled for this time period greatly influenced Johann Hamman and Goethe. A poem set during this time period recalls “how oft, at school, with most believing mind, / Presageful,” the speaker had watched for a “fluttering stranger!” This time period, which titles the best-known poem by Edward Young, is also the setting of a poem that imagines how “all seasons shall be sweet to” its addressee, the speaker’s cradled infant. That poem set during this time period describes a phenomenon that “performs its secret ministry, / Unhelped by any wind.” For 10 points, a Coleridge poem about frost is set during what time of day? ","answer":"ANSWER: nighttime [or midnight; accept “Frost at Midnight” or “Night-Thoughts”] <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"7. In May 2019, a ruling on the criminal status of homosexuality is expected to be issued by the high court of, for 10 points, what African country which held its first ever pride event in 2012 at the US embassy in Nairobi? ","answer":"ANSWER: Kenya [or Republic of Kenya; or Jamhuri ya Kenya] <Current Events> 4/18/2019 Play-In Game - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/1O09LlDOk8qhoQGZ6oOZSMbX2yy5qY5yc32miDANiwPU/edit 4/12 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Play-In Game |Page 4 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"9. This actress caresses several walls and paintings, hugs a bedpost, and sniffs her sheets in a scene in which she declares that she is “memorizing” a room where she had just spent several days in bed with a lover. In a later film, this actress puts on a toilet plunger–shaped ladies’ hat that she was initially disgusted by when she first spotted it in a shop window. The “Platonic idea of the human creature” can be seen in an extreme close-up of this actress’s face as she stands at the bow of a ship, according to an essay from Roland Barthes’s Mythologies examining her role as the title character of the film Queen Christina. A penniless baron connives to steal the jewels of an over-the-hill Russian ballerina played by this actress in the film Grand Hotel, in which this woman iconically exclaims, “I want to be alone.” For 10 points, name this Swedish-born Hollywood actress of the 1920s and 30s. ","answer":"ANSWER: Greta Garbo [or Greta Lovisa Gustafsson] <Other Fine Arts> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"0. An acetyl·methoxy ester derivative of this compound is commonly used for assays of multi-drug resistance due to its ability to enter cells and its hydrolyzed derivative being unable to exit. A diacetyl derivative of this compound is used with propidium iodide in cell viability assays that measure its hydrolysis. This compound is used to produce angiograms of the retina with shallower patterns than would be produced with indocyanine green. A derivative of this molecule with a carboxyl group at its 6 position is a popular beacon or quencher for phos·pho·ram·id·ite oligo·nucleo·tide synthesis as well as for real-time PCR. This molecule is typically functionalized with an iso·thio·cyanate group, producing a compound with excitation and emission wavelengths of respectively 495 and 519 nanometers. For 10 points, FAM and FITC are derivatives of what molecule named for a luminescent process? ","answer":"ANSWER: fluorescein [accept 6-carboxyfluorescein; accept fluorescein isothiocyanate; prompt on calcein] <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"5. Activists from one country erected a \"statue of peace\" commemorating the plight of these people in front of another country's embassy. The first station for these people was established at the request of Okamura Yasuji of the Shanghai Expeditionary Force. For 10 points, give this term for the mostly-Korean women forced to serve in brothels for Japanese soldiers. ","answer":"ANSWER: comfort women [or ianfu; or weian fu; or wianbu; prompt on anything involving women forced into prostitution by the Japanese military; prompt on things like Korean women] <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"2. In a later book, a philosopher quotes this author’s line “steer away from an unfamiliar word as if it were a reef” as an admonition against the pretentious speech of a student. The book Attic Nights preserves fragments from this author’s grammatical treatise De Analogia, written in support of his elegantia style. This man spoke of his descent both from “kings” and from “the gods, who hold sway over the kings themselves,” in his celebrated eulogy for his aunt. This writer claimed to have seen a one-horned deer, elk without joints, and the ox-like urus in the Hercynian forest. This author emphasizes his policy of clemency in the shorter counterpart to his best-known work, whose “clean and lucid brevity” was lauded by Cicero. Aulus Hirtius wrote the eighth book of a work by this man, which opens by describing a land split into three parts between the Belgae, Aquitani and the Celts. For 10 points, name this author of a commentary on the Gallic Wars, which his armies won. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gaius Julius Caesar [prompt on Caesar] <Other Academic> 4/18/2019 Play-In Game - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/1O09LlDOk8qhoQGZ6oOZSMbX2yy5qY5yc32miDANiwPU/edit 5/12 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Play-In Game |Page 5 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"3. The morphine-addicted anarchist-poet Davide Segre appears in a faux-documentary novel from this country that ends with a boy dying of an epileptic fit and his sheepdog Bella being shot. Two brothers who spend most of a novel from this country inviting girls to ride in their model 1100 car arrive at the wedding of one of the main characters in the last scene with a pair of shoes that she and her brother had handcrafted. An author from this country followed the aftermath of a German soldier’s rape of the half-Jewish Ida in her novel History. That author from this country inspired the pen name of an author from this country who wrote about Lenu’s relationship with Lila in books with famously “chick lit”-reminiscent covers. This country is home to an author whose identity may have been revealed in a controversial 2016 article; that author wrote My Brilliant Friend. For 10 points, name this home country of Elsa Morante and Elena Ferrante. ","answer":"ANSWER: Italy <European Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"4. Whitehead’s Process and Reality draws on this text’s distinction between “what always is and never becomes” and “what becomes and never is.” This text is said to conceptualize the cosmos as emerging from a “Self-Transcending Fecundity” and is cited as originating the “principle of plenitude” in the first chapter of Arthur Lovejoy’s The Great Chain of Being. This text uses the analogies of a lump of gold and a mother to explain a receptacle it calls a “third kind.” Julia Kristeva used another term for that space, chora, to describe a presignifying realm. Through Chalicidius’s translation, this text was the only work of its author available in the early middle ages, whose thinkers were fond of analyzing the cross shape attributed to the world-soul in this text. In this dialogue, the title character describes the demiurge’s creation of the universe and claims that the elements are made from regular polyhedra. A description of Atlantis also appears in, for 10 points, what cosmological Socratic dialogue? ","answer":"ANSWER: Timaeus <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"5. The mean free path of these waves is primarily limited by the size of the sample in the Casimir limit regime. An approximate expression for the energy density of these waves is proportional to an integral of the form x-cubed over quantity e to the x minus 1, where x is a dimensionless temperature ratio. One type of these waves has a y-intercept at the square root of quantity 2 times the force constant over the reduced mass on a dispersion plot. The negative logarithmic derivative of the frequency of one mode of these waves with respect to volume is equal to the Grüneisen parameter for that mode. A photon can gain energy by scattering off one of these waves in an anti-Stokes shift. A linear diatomic chain allows for an “optical” branch of these waves with nonzero frequency despite having zero crystal momentum. These collective excitations are assumed to have a linear dispersion relation in the Debye model for specific heat. For 10 points, name these quantized lattice vibrations of a solid crystal. ","answer":"ANSWER: phonons <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"6. This woman narrates a play in which she praises Sean O’Casey’s commitment to “believ[ing] people so completely,” as actors performing scenes from Juno and the Paycock remain frozen onstage. One of this author’s characters cries: “I care! I care about it all. It takes too much energy not to care!” as he decides to back a reform-minded political candidate. A photograph of this writer is the backdrop to a play that splices in material from her work, including scenes in which a man yells “DAMN MY EGGS -- DAMN ALL THE EGGS THAT EVER WAS” and flails around an imaginary “FLAMING SPEAR” chanting “OCOMOGOSIAY!!” After this author’s death, her husband Robert Nemiroff edited her unpublished interviews and letters into the play To Be Young, Gifted, and Black. In a play by this author, Willy Harris scams Walter Lee out of money to open a liquor store, but his family still moves to a white neighborhood in Chicago. For 10 points, name this author who wrote about the Younger family in A Raisin in the Sun. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lorraine (Vivian) Hansberry <American Literature> 4/18/2019 Play-In Game - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/1O09LlDOk8qhoQGZ6oOZSMbX2yy5qY5yc32miDANiwPU/edit 6/12 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Play-In Game |Page 6 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"7. Heinrich Schütz wrote a composition in this genre that replaced the standard plainsong with “neo-Gregorian” recitative. When writing a work in this genre, the composer changed some of the text from B. H. Brockes’ libretto, such as the words “leave Aschshaph’s dens of murder” to “leave your dens of torment.” The shortest aria in a composition in this genre unusually accents the second beat of many measures, and places emphasis on “mein” in “Ach, mein sinn.” In one of these works, the soloist sings a certain text in German in E-flat minor, but in the text’s original Hebrew in B-flat minor. In some works in this genre, a tenor narrates the story in recitative as the Evangelist, and a central character is often accompanied by a string quartet in a “halo” effect. For 10 points, name these works that tell the story of Jesus’ crucifixion, such as two by Bach setting the Gospels of Matthew and John. ","answer":"ANSWER: passions [prompt on historia; prompt on oratorio] <Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"8. In Trinidad and Tobago, brightly colored models called Tadjah are built and later thrown into the sea during this observance, which in the Caribbean is often known as Hosay. According to al-Bukhari, Muhammad said that Muslims had more claim to Moses than Jews did, and therefore designated this day as a fast day. As part of this event, professional performers read aloud from texts such as the Rawdat al-Shuhada. A sword inscribed with poetry is the centerpiece of an extremely heavy stylized banner called the alam that is paraded around during this event. Some participants in processions on this day pound their chests instead of taking part in tatbir by flagellating themselves with chains, knives, or razors. On this day, Shia pilgrims visit a tomb near the site of the Battle of Karbala. For 10 points, name this Muslim holiday in on the tenth day of Muharram that commemorates the killing of Husayn ibn Ali. ","answer":"ANSWER: Day of Ashura [or Yom Ashura; or Tabuik; or Tabot; or Hosay until “Hosay” is read; until “Muharram” is read, accept Mourning of Muharram or Muharram Observances or Remembrance of Muharram; prompt on Muharram alone] <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"9. The laboratory of David J. Anderson identified an inhibitory microcircuit in this structure mediated by protein kinase C-delta expressing cells in its CE1 region. In the 1950s, John Downer performed experiments with rhesus monkeys from which one of these structures had been removed. Much of what is known about this structure comes from studying a female sufferer of Urbach-Wiethe disease known only as “Patient S.M.” Joseph LeDoux showed that projections from the central nuclei of this structure to the reticular formation mediate freezing behavior in rats, which can happen by a fast “low road” leading directly from the thalamus to this structure. The basolateral complex, which makes up the majority of this structure, receives inputs from other parts of the medial temporal lobe, like the hippocampus. For 10 points, name these two almond-shaped structures involved in emotional responses such as fear. ","answer":"ANSWER: amygdala [or central nucleus of the amygdala; or basolateral complex before it is mentioned; prompt on medial temporal lobe before it is mentioned] <Biology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"0. This event is the subject of a “Secret History” written by Nicholas Cullather. The CEUA student group painted the number 32, for Article 32 of the constitution, to support this event. This event was justified in part by the discovery of weapons on the MS Alfhem. Whiting Willauer furnished aircraft from Civil Air Transport to participate in this event, during which David Atlee Phillips led a radio station called the “Voice of Liberation.” Soldiers in Zacapa critically refused to fight against this event. It was provoked by concern over the passage of Decree 900 and the presence of Jose Manuel Fortuny’s PGT party in government. This event brought to an end the “Ten Years of Spring” and installed a dictatorship under Carlos Castillo Armas. Its code name was Operation PBSUCCESS. For 10 points, name this 1954 event supported by the United Fruit Company that toppled the President of Guatemala. ","answer":"ANSWER: Coup d'etat against Jacobo Arbenz [accept Operation PBSUCCESS before mention; accept 1954 Guatemala Coup and prompt on 54 Guatemala Coup before “1954”; accept overthrow or similar words for “Coup”] <World History> 4/18/2019 Play-In Game - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/1O09LlDOk8qhoQGZ6oOZSMbX2yy5qY5yc32miDANiwPU/edit 7/12 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Play-In Game |Page 7 Bonuses "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Name this poetic form exemplified by The Owl and the Nightingale and The Parlement of Foules. This type of poem is often contrasted with dialogue poetry. ","answer":"ANSWER: debate poetry [accept argument poetry or contention poetry; prompt on dialogue poetry before it is read] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] The Parlement of Foules is also classified as this type of poem, due to it using one of these phenomena as a framing device. Piers Plowman experiences several of these things. ","answer":"ANSWER: a dream [or dream vision; accept just vision] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] The aisling [AHSH-ling] is a type of dream vision poem from this country. Seamus Heaney, an author from this country, described his poem “The Disappearing Island” as an aisling “inflected with irony.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Ireland [or Eire] <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Name this family whose members included Catharine, the author of A Treatise on Domestic Economy. A man from this family had his affair with Elizabeth Tilton exposed in Victoria Woodhull’s newspaper. ","answer":"ANSWER: Beecher [or Catharine Beecher; or Henry Ward Beecher] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] In her “Circular Addressed to the Benevolent Ladies of the United States,” Catharine Beecher urged women to oppose this Jackson Administration policy, which resulted in the Trail of Tears. ","answer":"ANSWER: Indian Removal [or equivalents, such as forced resettlement of American Indians] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Goethe’s “The Sphere of Woman” was published in this women’s magazine, which was edited by the author of “Mary Had a Little Lamb,” Sarah Josepha Hale. It published stories like “The Cask of Amontillado” as the most popular periodical of the antebellum period. ","answer":"ANSWER: Godey’s Lady’s Book <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Name this Japanese religion founded by Nakayama Miki. Adherents attempt to sweep away eight negative “dusts” that accumulate in humans’ minds. ","answer":"ANSWER: Tenrikyo "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] According to Tenrikyo, humans underwent this process over generations after they came into being. It’s not related to lifespan, but Jains hold that humans are currently experiencing the opposite of this change, but will begin undergoing it again when the ascending half of the time cycle, the utsarpini, begins. ","answer":"ANSWER: getting taller [or getting larger; accept anything indicating increasing in size] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] To explain the nature of the monotheistic God of Tenrikyo, Nakayama Miki used this word for spirits from traditional Shinto belief. ","answer":"ANSWER: kami <Religion> 4/18/2019 Play-In Game - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/1O09LlDOk8qhoQGZ6oOZSMbX2yy5qY5yc32miDANiwPU/edit 8/12 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Play-In Game |Page 8 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Name these ceramic materials made of iron oxide mixed with another metal such as manganese. They are popular materials for the cores of inductors and transformers because of their low eddy current losses. ","answer":"ANSWER: ferrites [prompt on “ferrimagnets”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] The residual alignment in ferrites overwhelms this other form of magnetism, which is present in all atoms and arises from changes in electron orbits acting in opposition to an applied field. When strong enough, it can levitate matter. ","answer":"ANSWER: diamagnetism "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] This theorem states that classical mechanics cannot truly explain diamagnetism because in thermal equilibrium the average magnetization for a classical electron gas is zero. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bohr-van Leeuwen theorem <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Name this company that was sued for gender discrimination by a class of women represented by lead plaintiff Betty Dukes, leading to a 2011 Supreme Court opinion. ","answer":"ANSWER: Walmart [or Walmart Inc.; or Wal-Mart Stores, Inc.; accept The People’s Republic of Walmart or Wal-Mart (Stores, Inc.) v. Dukes or Dukes v. Wal-Mart (Stores, Inc.)] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"3. ","answer":"ANSWER: class certification [accept answers mentioning forms of the word certify] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] The drudgery of working in a Minneapolis Walmart store makes up much of the latter chapters of the book Nickel and Dimed by this writer, whose follow-up book, Bait and Switch, described her efforts to become employed in corporate America. ","answer":"ANSWER: Barbara Ehrenreich [accept Barbara Alexander] <Social Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Name this brief Kafka story devoted to a description of Odradek, a creature shaped like a spool of thread whose laughter sounds “like the rustling of fallen leaves.” ","answer":"ANSWER: “The Cares of a Family Man” [accept any translations along the lines of “A Problem for the Father of the Family” or “The Sorrows of the Paterfamilias”; or “Die Sorge des Hausvaters”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Odradek is one of the creatures described in the Book of Imaginary Beings by Martina Guerrero and this blind Argentinian author. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jorge Luis Borges "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Zachary McCaltex and Twang Panattapam search for treasure in the novel The Sinking of the Odradek Stadium by Harry Matthews, the only American member of this group. Gilbert Adair is best known for translating a lipogrammatic novel by a member of this group. ","answer":"ANSWER: Oulipo <European Literature> 4/18/2019 Play-In Game - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/1O09LlDOk8qhoQGZ6oOZSMbX2yy5qY5yc32miDANiwPU/edit 9/12 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Play-In Game |Page 9 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Name this philosophical problem that concerns how to differentiate scientific and non-scientific disciplines. Karl Popper posited the criterion of falsifiability as a solution to this problem. ","answer":"ANSWER: the demarcation problem "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] This German word often translated as “science” appears in the title of Fichte’s Foundations of the Science of Knowledge. Kant argued that the “schöne [this term],” or “fine sciences,” were aesthetic judgments that did not count as true science. ","answer":"ANSWER: wissenschaft [accept variants like wissenschaftliche or wissenschaftslehre or wissenschaften; accept Wissenschaftslehre] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Thomas F. Gieryn coined this term for the creation of divisions between disciplines, arguing that it can be explained in terms of scientists’ attempts to mold the public image of science. ","answer":"ANSWER: boundary-work <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Name these recurring musical themes, which can represent people, objects, or abstract concepts. ","answer":"ANSWER: leitmotif [accept leitmotives, prompt on “motif” or “motives”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] One of the most recognizable leitmotifs is the 6/8 [“six eight”] time horn call of this character, which he plays after failing to mimic a bird with his reed flute in Act II of an opera named for him. ","answer":"ANSWER: Siegfried "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Another brassy leitmotif, first heard in the fourth scene of Das Rheingold, is for this object, which always starts with a descending octave leap before continuing with an arpeggio. ","answer":"ANSWER: sword <Other Fine Arts> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Name this newspaper founded in 1904 by Jean Jaures, whose slogan is “In an ideal world, [this newspaper] would not exist.” It holds a yearly “Festival” in September to raise money to cover its costs. ","answer":"ANSWER: L’Humanite [or Humanity] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] L’Humanite is the organ of this political party, which was founded in part by Ho Chi Minh and was led for a long time by Maurice Thorez. It is closely allied with French General Confederation of Labor, or CGT. ","answer":"ANSWER: French Communist party [or PCF] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] During a strike under this government that led to the signing of the Matignon Agreements, L’Humanite published that “one must know when to end a strike.” This government was led by the first Jewish Prime Minister of France. ","answer":"ANSWER: Popular Front [Front Populaire; prompt on French Third Republic or La Troisieme Republique; prompt on Premiership or government of Andre Leon Blum] <European History> 4/18/2019 Play-In Game - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/1O09LlDOk8qhoQGZ6oOZSMbX2yy5qY5yc32miDANiwPU/edit 10/12 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Play-In Game |Page 10 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Name this class of complexes designed for polyolefin production. Their namesake property occurs due to the presence of a pi-bonded ligand being linked to other ligands on the central metal. ","answer":"ANSWER: constrained geometry complex [accept CGC] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Constrained geometry complexes have a small value for this measurement, which refers to the angle between the binding sites and the metal for a bidentate ligand. ","answer":"ANSWER: bite angle "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Bidentate ligands, like other polydentate ligands, undergo this process in which a ligand forms multiple coordinate bonds with a single atom. EDTA’s ability to undergo this process allows it to sequester calcium ions. ","answer":"ANSWER: chelation [accept word forms such as chelate] <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Name this short story in which Mrs. Roby gets the shallowly intellectual Lunch Club to pretend to be fascinated by the title entity, which is actually just a river Mrs. Roby used to live near. ","answer":"ANSWER: “Xingu” "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] The author of “Xingu” also wrote this story about Grace Ansley and Alida Slade, old rivals in love who return to the title city after first meeting there twenty-five years prior. ","answer":"ANSWER: “Roman Fever” [10] “Xingu” and “Roman Fever” are by this author, who set several stories in her native New York. She also used New York as the setting of her novel The House of Mirth. "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Identify this country where fashionable men were outfitted with suits on Savile Row. ","answer":"ANSWER: United Kingdom [or Great Britain; or England] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] This British fashion icon from between the wars was often photographed wearing a turtleneck or polka-dot dressing gown and smoking a cigarette with a very long holder. He wrote the lyrics to many popular songs, such as “I’ll See You Again” and “Mad About the Boy.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Noel Coward [or Sir Noel Peirce Coward] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Coward once dispensed extremely condescending fashion advice to Cecil Beaton, who went on to win Oscars for Costume Design for My Fair Lady and for this film. This 1958 film directed by Vincente Minnelli begins with Maurice Chevalier singing “Thank Heaven for Little Girls.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Gigi <Other Academic> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Name this non-radical, non-ion reactive oxygen species that is produced by chlorophyll during photosynthesis, where it is almost immediately quenched by carotenoids. ","answer":"ANSWER: singlet oxygen [or 1O2; or dioxygen(singlet); or dioxidene; prompt on oxygen] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] In the walls of arteries, singlet oxygen contributes to the oxidation of the LDL that transports this lipid, leading to atherosclerosis. ","answer":"ANSWER: cholesterol "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Histidine has been shown to scavenge singlet oxygen, partly mitigating the “reperfusion injury” that often follows this condition, in which restriction of blood supply to a tissue starves it of oxygen. ","answer":"ANSWER: ischemia [prompt on hypoxia] <Biology> 4/18/2019 Play-In Game - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/1O09LlDOk8qhoQGZ6oOZSMbX2yy5qY5yc32miDANiwPU/edit 11/12 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Play-In Game |Page 11 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Name these early secular musicians in France and Occitania, whose songs often discussed “courtly” love. ","answer":"ANSWER: troubadours [or trouvères or trobairitzes] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] The troubadour and trouvère songs may have been inspired by the nuba musical genre, which is often accompanied by the oud and is sung in this language. ","answer":"ANSWER: Arabic [or al-ʻarabiyyah] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Troubadour songs are usually in this general form, which sets several stanzas to the same melody, often in an AAB pattern. Through-composed songs have the opposite of this form. ","answer":"ANSWER: strophic <Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Name this Oscan-speaking Italian tribe that fought Rome in three wars in the fourth and third centuries B.C. They forced a Roman army to go “under the yoke” after the Battle of Caudine Forks. ","answer":"ANSWER: Samnites "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] When the sacred chickens ominously refused to eat prior to this naval battle from the First Punic War, Publius Claudius Pulcher shouted, “Let them drink!” and threw them overboard. Rome lost. ","answer":"ANSWER: Battle of Drepana [or Battle of Drepanum] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Rome’s sacred geese alerted Marcus Manlius to this man’s attack on the Capitoline Hill during the Gallic sack of Rome. This Gallic chieftain cried “Woe to the conquered!” during a dispute over the fee Rome had to pay. ","answer":"ANSWER: Brennus <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] One Laodamia killed herself out of grief after receiving a postmortem visit from this warrior, her husband, who was the first Greek to step onto the shore at Troy and was thus the first to die in the war. ","answer":"ANSWER: Protesilaus "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] According to the Iliad, Sarpedon was the son of a Laodamia who was herself the daughter of this hero. With the help of Pegasus and a big block of lead, this hero slew the Chimera. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bellerophon [or Bellerophontes] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] A scholium on the Odyssey lists a Laodamia among the daughters of this Spartan prince, who forced would-be suitors to beat him in a footrace to win the right to marry his daughter Penelope, at which Odysseus succeeded. ","answer":"ANSWER: Icarius <Myth> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Name these devices which include AMANDA and ANTARES. \"Ring-imaging\" variants of them work by recording the Cherenkov radiation caused by the activation of photomultiplier tubes. ","answer":"ANSWER: neutrino detectors [or neutrino telescopes; prompt on particle detectors] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Masatoshi Koshiba was given part of the 2002 Nobel Prize in Physics for his work in using the Super-Kamiokande to detect neutrinos from the “Large” one of this pair of dwarf galaxies orbiting the Milky Way. ","answer":"ANSWER: Magellanic Clouds [or Nubeculae Magellani] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Many neutrino detectors, such as ANITA, also work by detecting this radiation, which results from particles traveling faster than the speed of light in a dielectric generating a collection of secondary particles that themselves have a charge anisotropy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Askaryan Effect [or Askaryan Radiation] <Other Science> 4/18/2019 Play-In Game - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/1O09LlDOk8qhoQGZ6oOZSMbX2yy5qY5yc32miDANiwPU/edit 12/12 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Play-In Game |Page 12 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Name this world leader sometimes called “The Great Crocodile,” who declared that his country must “adapt or die” a year after defeating Connie Mulder to become leader of the National Party. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pieter Willem “P. W.” Botha "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Another mysterious assassination in African history was that of Laurent Kabila, a president of this country who was shot in his office in 2001 four years after succeeding Mobutu Sese Seko. ","answer":"ANSWER: Democratic Republic of the Congo [or the DRC; prompt on the Congo; do not accept the “Republic of Congo”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"5. Ronen Bergman’s 2018 book Rise and Kill First alleges that he was killed in a Mossad safe house by Moroccan intelligence operatives and French police officers. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mehdi Ben Barka <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Name this figure who appears in a cycle of frescoes in Orvieto Cathedral, in which he can be seen resurrecting a man and standing atop a marble column as a malignant figure whispers into his ear. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Antichrist "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Luca Signorelli’s cycle depicting the sermon and deeds of the Antichrist includes The Last Judgment, which is thought to have inspired this artist’s own version of the scene, which features a self-portrait as the flayed skin of St. Bartholomew. ","answer":"ANSWER: Michelangelo (di Lodovico) Buonarotti (Simoni) [accept either underlined name] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Some scholars believe that the Antichrist is actually a portrait of this historical figure. He is the subject of a portrait by Fra Bartolomeo, who, for five years, renounced painting in accordance with this man’s teachings. ","answer":"ANSWER: Girolamo Savonarola <Painting and Sculpture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] Name this mystical sect whose poets Hafez and Rumi often wrote love poems expressing desire for union with the Beloved. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sufism [accept the Mevlevi order] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] A poem in ibn Arabi’s The Interpreter of Desires addresses the command “gentle now” to these animals “of the thornberry and moringa thicket.” Ibn Hazm’s treatise on love is titled for the “neck-ring” of this sort of animal. ","answer":"ANSWER: doves [prompt on birds] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"PlayIn","question":"[10] The “gentle moaning Turtle-dove” is one of the birds addressed at the beginning of this Sufi author’s long poem The Conference of the Birds. ","answer":"ANSWER: Attar of Nishapur [or Farīd ud-Dīn Attar; or Abū Ḥamīd bin Abū Bakr Ibrāhīm] <World Literature>"}]
